An army of forgotten heroes, all officially dead. They live
for combat. Now they've met the wrong man.
Extreme Prejudice is a action, thriller, crime film directed by Walter Hill.
Lean, mean Texas Ranger Jack Benteen locks horns with a former
friend, Cash Bailey, now a ruthless drug kingpin.
Though they're on opposite sides of the law, they share
a love interest in the sensual Sarita.
When a crew of rogue soldiers descends upon the border town for an off-the-books mission, all roads lead to a
bloody, to-the-death showdown, as loyalties shift and the lines between good and evil are blurred.
Jack Benteen, played by Nick Nolte.
Cash Bailey, played by Powers Boothe.
Major Paul Hackett, played by Michael Ironside.
Sarita Cisneros, played by María Conchita Alonso.
Sheriff Hank Pearson, played by Rip Torn.
Sgt. Larry McRose, played by Clancy Brown.
Extreme Prejudice is a 1987 American neo-Western action thriller film directed by Walter Hill, from a
screenplay by Harry Kleiner and Deric Washburn, from a story by John Milius and Fred Rexer.
It stars Nick Nolte and Powers Boothe, with a supporting cast including Michael
Ironside, María Conchita Alonso, Rip Torn, William Forsythe, and Clancy Brown.
Set in South Texas near the U.S.-Mexico border, the film's plot centers on the conflict between two former friends-turned-rivals, one a Texas Ranger
(Nolte) and one a drug trafficker (Boothe), who both become embroiled in a political conspiracy involving a black ops military unit.
The film was released by Tri-Star Pictures on April 24, 1987.
It received a positive critical response, but was not a financial success.
Extreme Prejudice is an homage, of sorts, to The Wild Bunch, a western
directed by Sam Peckinpah, with whom Hill worked on The Getaway.
Both films end with a massive gunfight in a Mexican border town.
The title originates from "terminate with extreme prejudice", a phrase
popularized by Apocalypse Now, also written by Milius.
The film explores themes of robbery, texas, mexican
standoff, texas ranger, organized crime.
The tone is dark and emotional and intense.